Ivanka Please tell me how many
Иванка Скажи пожалуйста сколько
Ukrainians have moved to the Russian Federation in recent years I
украинцев в последние года переехало в
am answering Ukrainians The
Российскую Федерацию отвечаю украинцам
Russian Federation is not needed so no
Российская Федерация на не нужна поэтому
one is
никто в
going there Hello Hello to you And we have already
едет Здравствуйте Привет тебе А мы уже с
talked to you well wait don't
тобой общались ну подожди не
switch I have one question for you
Переключайся у меня к тебе один вопрос
I just talked to a guy
такой я сейчас просто с чуваком
and he asked me A question like this
поговорил и он мене задал Вопрос такой
correspondent account what is it
корреспондентский счёт что это такое
Tell me you idiot I
Расскажи мне [__] по корреспондентский
don't know about a correspondent account most likely it is from a
счёт не знаю с скорее всего это из
bank if you have for example
банковской если у Вас например
uh there is an account in dollars in a Ukrainian
ээ там вот счёт в долларах в украинском
bank you need to transfer via SWIFT to
банке вам вам чтобы перекинули по свифту
you through a correspondent bank for example A
вам через банк-корреспондент например
bank in the USA to which your bank brings
Банк в США на который ваш банк приводит
dollars and it transfers dollars to your bank
доллар а он переводит доллар на ваш банк
in Ukraine for example Well for example what uh Well
в Украину например Ну например че
I get it So for an ordinary
ээ Ну я понял Значит для обычного
person as such a correspondent
человека как таковой корреспондентский
account is not needed I don't know Look I don't
счёт он не нужен Я не знаю Смотри я не
know what's there for an ordinary person I
знаю что там для обычного человека я
know that If according to the Swift system Yes it seems
знаю что Если по системе Swift Да вроде
uh from one currency for example the
ээ из одной вот валюте например
United States or the currency there the euro uh
Соединённых Штатов или валюте там евро э
from one uh say jurisdiction to another
из одного ээ скаже юрисдикции в другую
transfer money Yes, for example, in Ukraine, a
переводят деньги Да например в Украин
Ukrainian bank, for example, PrivatBank, it
украинский банк например ПриватБанк он
has a correspondent bank
имеет банк корреспондент
there, Mogan, it means it has some kind of
там моган там значит он имеет какой-то
correspondent account, that's what it's
там корреспондентский счёт вот это вот
called, a correspondent account, so
так называется корреспондентский сч
if this turns out to be a gasket bank
если это получается это банк прокладка
Well, roughly, let's take it not a gasket, like a
Ну грубо так возьмём не прокладка как бы
bank More precisely, not a gasket, a distributor that
банк Точнее не прокладка дистриб который
transfers your money, a connector, yes, a connector I see Well, again we
переводит твои деньги конектор такой да
say no Or further Well,
говорим нет Или дальше Ну говорите
just say I didn't understand why we will communicate, no, well, we communicate So we are
просто я не понял почему общаться будем
with you Here are
нет ну так общаемся Так мы же с тобой
you from Where are you from We have already tried to
Вот Вы откуда Мы с тобой уже пытались
communicate, if in my memory, about
общаться если на моей памяти где-то раз
five times I don't remember you at all Where are you from Is it
пять я вас вообще не помню вы откуда Что
true that Vologda Yes Cherepovets What are you doing,
правда что ли волог Да Череповец Ты
why do I remember you, so I do
что почему Я тебя помню значит я такое
n't mean such a thing to you,
не значение для тебя може
maybe I understood, what do you think, why is Russia
возможно понял как считаете почему Росси
at war Russia and Ukraine
воюет Россия и Украина
mother,
мать
okay, the opposite question, I'm tired of
хорошо обратный вопрос мне надоело
asking This is not tired of me, I'm like a robot,
задавать Вот это не надоело я как робот
territories and people I
территории и люди Всё я
answered That is, Russia needs territories
ответил То есть России нужны территории
and people
и люди
Yes, I understand, in Russia we have
Да понима у нас в России
few
мм мало
people, mm, but here it turns out that in 10 years, plus 10
людей а тут получается за 10 лет плюс 10
million people,
лямов человек
just plus territories on which  there are
просто плюс территории на которых есть
good
хорошие
fossils everything is fine And where did you
ископаемые всё прекрасно А где вы
count 10
насчитали 10
million Well, let's count
лямов Ну давай посчитаем
Let's 2.8
Давайте 2,8
Crimeans there were not so many in Ukraine
крымчан там столько не было в Украине
even I mean 2 and 3 about 2 million people
даже В смысле 2 и3 около 2 Милн людей
Well 2 million okay let's take Crimea 2
было Ну 2 милна хорошо возьмём Крым 2
million 2
милна 2
million Luhansk Donetsk region Well, another
млн Луганская Донецкая область Ну ещё с
3 million from each this is already even according to these
каждой по 3 милна это уже даже по этим
estimates with a stretched howl would be
оценкам с натянутым воем было
at least with
бы как минимум с
UPP look Donetsk Donetsk region Russia
упп смотри Донец Донецкой области Россия
captured only a little
захватила только чуть-чуть
most of the Donetsk region is not in Russia
большинство Донецкой области не в России
wait a minute out of a hundred more from those
нутом подожди из сто ещё из тех
territories so the same people left for
территорий так само люди по уезжали в
Ukraine where did you get this 10 million
Украину откуда у вас это 10 млн
And you have data Well, you have the
А у тебя есть данные Ну у тебя же есть
Internet Yes uh Look how many
Интернет есть Да э Посмотри сколько
Ukrainians went to the Russian Federation
украинцев ехало в Российскую Федерацию
How many during the
Сколько за время
war Well, just the difference, about 10 million
войны Ну просто разни сжи около 10 млн
just Ukrainians
просто украинцев
Yes what did she do she entered this from what year to
Да что сделала въехала это с какого по
what year Well, just
какой год Ну ты просто
look In what period did she
посмотри В какой период
enter Well, over the past 6 years Open
въехала Ну за последние 6 лет Открой
statistics what is meant entered
статистику что имеется в виду въехало
if a person went there and back 10 times
если человек 10 раз ездил туда назад
how many times to
сколько его раз
count Listen
посчитать Слушай
maybe they crossed the border or stayed to
возможно пересекли границу или остались
live in Russia
жить в России
and are there such such information
а есть такие такая есть информаци ещё
again look if a person for example yes from
раз смотри если человек например да из
Donetsk left entered left entered left entered left For
Донец выехал въехал выехал въехал выехал
example, as they say from
выехал Вот например как говорят из
Ukraine to Poland there 2 million
Украины в Польшу там выехало 2 млн
people left from Poland to Ukraine There are 1700 for example
человек из Польши в Украину Там 1700
for this month for example
например вот за этот месяц например
yes I heard I watched Ukrainian I speak
да я слышал Я смотрел украинские я говор
How do you count these 10 million look 10
Как вы счита вот эти 10 мил смотри 10
million left you go well returned 1n 700
млн выехало ты го ну вернулось 1н 700
again That is, what do you think this is the
ещё раз То есть ты считаешь это что за
number that crossed the border can you
число что пересекала границу можешь мне
show me the news I'm interested I'm telling you I'm telling
новость показать мне интересно я тебе я
you about something else don't give it to me come on no no don't
тебе о другом не давай давай не не не
give it to me look come on no so that we can
давай смотри давай нет чтобы мы
discuss Find what news I'll
обсуждали Найди какую новость я сейчас
watch it now about these 10 million Let's
её посмотрю про эти 10 млн Давай чтобы
talk about something real Listen do you trust Google too
говорили Слушай ты Гуглу веришь тоже
come on tell me I'll read I'll open myself this
давай скажи я прочитаю открою себя эту
news too
новость тоже
So let's just now I'll open
Так давай просто вот я сейчас открою
Google and ask him Okay
Google ему задам Окей
Google doesn't work you see here in
Google не работает видишь вот у нас в
Russia it doesn't
России он не
work we need to open it Okay
работает его нам надо открыть Окей
Google how many
Google сколько
Ukrainians arrived According to sources in the
украинцев приехало Согласно источни
Krasnoyarsk Territory there are 45 ml of
Красноярского края насчитывается 45 мл
Ukraine
украи
This is not it at all
Это вообще не
I haven't had time yet she already you understand
то я ещё не успел она уже понимаешь
began to
начала
answer Let's try again Yes
отвечать Давай попробуем ещё раз
Okay Google how many Ukrainians
Дава Окей Google сколько украинцев
entered and received citizenship of the
въехало и получило гражданство
Russian Federation over the past 3
Российской Федерации за последние 3
years no
года нет
he you understand she already turns out according to my
он понимаешь она уже получается по моим
these how many when it doesn't
этим сколько когда она не так
work like that how many Ukrainians received citizenship of the Russian Federation over the
работает сколько украинцев получило
past 3
последние 3
years how many Ukrainians received
года сколько украинцев получило
citizenship of the Russian Federation over the
гражданство Российской Федерации за
past 3 years
последние 3 года
about the Ministry of Foreign Affairs Report in 2019 98,000 in 2020
о МИД Сообщи в 2019 году 98.000 в 2020
656,000 Well, listen with this you can u let him
656 000 Ну ну слушай с этим можно у
say let him say Google Let Google
пусть скажет пусть скажет Google Пусть
say with his voice I Google I'm in Google
Google скажет голосом я Google я в Гугле
and I'm watching that come on to me Let him say with his
и смотрю ту давай мне Давай пусть
voice Google I do
голосом скажет
n't know what you're reading there
Google я не знаю что ты там читаешь вот
Google could read from you Come on
Google умел у тебя читать Давай
tell me now
говори сейчас
now how many Ukrainians have received Russian citizenship in the last 3
сейчас сколько украинцев за последние 3
years
года получили
So let's she doesn't say
Федерации Так давай она не говорит
Okay let's ask now I have one too
Окей сейчас спросим у меня тоже есть
So Ivanka Please tell me how many
Так Иванка Скажи пожалуйста сколько
Ukrainians have moved to the Russian Federation in the last few years
украинцев в последние года переехало в
I answer the Ukrainians The
Российскую Федерацию отвечаю украинцам
Russian Federation is not
Российская Федерация не
needed Whoever does
нужна Кто в
n't
эту не
go to this Well
едет Ну
listen
слушай
you no you're cool No it doesn't
ты нет ты прикольно Нет это так не
work like that really No no don't protest it
работает са правда Да нет не проте это
just shows your Well not
просто показывает твоё Ну как бы не
very much my complete victory No it's
очень сильно полная победа моя Нет это
not your victory Google still didn't
не победа твой Google так и ничего не
find anything but mine did come on
нашёл а мой нашёл давай
Hi man How are you How do you like this
Привет мужик Как те Как тебе этот
code cool cool really yeah And you
код прикольный прикольный правда да А
know his thing about the World Cup is that if
знаешь в ЧМ его фишка вот короче если
people like or don't like or don't
люди там лайкают не лайкают и не
donate he's so sad yeah
скидають донаты он вот такой грустный да
And when likes and donations are given up then he's cheerful
А когда лайки и донаты сда то он Весёлый
not me not Dona I don't like Yes it's not you it's me
не я не Дона я не лайкаю Да это не ты
I'm just looking for communication with
это это я просто общение ищу с помощью
your help normal adequate people
тебя нормальными адекватными людми
who don't swear don't send me far
которые не матерятся не отправляют меня
away And why should you be
куда подальше А за что вас надо
sent where
отправлять куда
far away Well, it happens that people send
подальше Ну бывает что люди отправляют
far away And for
куда подальше А за
what I dont
что не
know To each his own And his own is not for everyone right there is
знаю Каждому своё А своё не каждому
a saying To each his own And his own is not for everyone right and not To each his own
поговорка есть такая Каждому своё А своё
Well yes yes the meaning is the same and not his own to each not To each his own Yes
своё Ну да да смысл один и тот же и и не
how much can you do your own not to
своё Да сколько пере можно своё не
each yes yes yes your own not each To each his own to
каждому дадада своё не каж
each not or To each his own
Каждому своё каждому не или Каждому своё
you dont see we have three elements six combinations we can make More than six is not a permutation of six from three elements the factorial of the number three is not there it turns out now Ill tell you how it is geometry in this case I forgot everything khnar there were something sines cosines Well yes Well you understood me in short I do
косинусы Ну да Ну вы меня поняли короче
nt remember this word Sorry what well its
не помню это слово Извините что ну мне
really night for me Im not standing on the highway at all And
реально ночь я н вообще на трассе стою А
there this hypotenuse is rolling That was yes Well
там этот катит гипотенуза Вот это было
how can you tie it to them Well
да Ну ну как бы им можно привязать Ну
no this word is called differently What is the
нет по-другому это слово называется А
name of this theory
как называется это теория
that has no definite
которая нет определённого
end the difference in
конца разница
numbers the difference in concepts what is it
цифр разница понятий как она
called
называется-то
Damn well I really dont remember Sorry well I
Блин ну реально не помню Извините ну
forgot it Well remember Im interested
забыл я его А ну вспомните мне интересно
I  I wonder about these scientific
Мне вот интересно ваши эти научные
views of yours I want to read about them too
воззрения Я хочу тоже почитать о
Which one is this which you want to
Какое Вот это о котором вы хотите
remember I want to remember it too well uh the
вспомнить Я тоже хочу его вспомнить ну э
phrase is such that there is a meaning Everyone
фраза такая что там смысл Смысл каждый
understands their own meaning
понимает
and the essence of the phrase To each his own To
свой и суть фразы Каждому
each his own but his own not to
своё Каждому своё но своё не
each is correct and to each not his own Well
каждому правильно и каждому не
in principle yes Look in short
своё Ну в принципе да Смотри короче
let me simplify the combinations for you I
давай я тебе упрощать комбинации
will tell you look uh your own not to each Yes your own to
расскажу смотри
each not to each not to each his own not to each his own not and now not his own to each not to each his own
ээ своё не каждому Да своё каждому не
six combinations no no not in essence I
шесть комбинаций нене не по сути я
said two combinations To each his own but his own not to each Yes
сказал две комбинации Каждому своё но
but these are not complete
своё не каждому Да но это не полные
combinations you see there are more combinations
комбинации понимаешь комбинаций больше
inside the power the power hides from you the
нутри власть власть скрывает от вас
combinations carried zhda
комбинации несли жда
progression there you can have a semantic
прогрессия там можно смысловую
theory Just simply change and turn it
теорию Прям просто изменить и повернуть
in the other direction at all
вообще в другую сторону
correctly I even have a code excuse my
правильно У меня аж код извиняйте за мой
French to give in a geometric
французский дать в геометрической
progression the code is such
прогрессии код такой
that you understood a geometric progression
что ты понял геометрической прогрессии
because most people reason
потому что большинство людей рассуждает
reason in an arithmetic progression
рассуждают в арифметической прогрессии
and progressively you need to reason in a
а прогрессивно нужно рассуждать в
geometric
геометрической
progression Well yes this  few people understand
прогрессии Ну да это мало кто понимает
this theorem It's just easier for some to
эту теорему Просто некоторым проще
send As they say there than to just
послать Как говорится туда чем просто
discuss some
обсудить какую-то
topic Yes, this theorem is really simple
тему да эту теорему действительно просто
When you and I were studying at school, others
Мы когда с вами учились в школе другие
skipped this theorem It's clear what grade you were in This one
прогуливали эту теорему видно вы в каком
I actually finished all the grades and they kicked me out I
те я вобще се классов закончил и меня
believe it's just that my behavior was generally
верю просто у меня поведение вообще
tough In short, such a person was a
жёсткое такое было короче такой человек
hooligan, as it were, he fought, swore
хулиган как бы дрался постоянно ругался
there, somewhere he missed
там матерился где-то в голову пропускали
punches to the head, not a punch to the head And
удары не в удару в бошку не пропускал А
where did they miss Well, in general, as if nowhere,
куда пропускали Ну вообще как бы никуда
I was second in boxing in my youth How could
у меня юношеский второй по боксу Как бы
I miss at all, it's not an option at all I
мне вообще мне пропускать вообще не
understood Somewhere there were
понял где-то там в ДТП попадали
serious accidents, a head injury, there was a head injury Well,
серьёзные травма головы травма головы
yes, on December 1, I
была Ну да 1 декабря я стекло лобовое
knocked out the windshield with my head on this This Recently, yes, 2
выбил головой о это вот это Недавно да 2
weeks ago Well,
недели назад Ну
yes, I understand everything now In short, we thought
да Всё тепер понял это короче задумались
about geometric progression somewhere, the
об геометрической прогрессии где-то
philosophy of numbers No, it was a matter of chance,
философии чисел Нет там дело случая было
that is, the theory of probability, we discussed the
то есть теории вероятности рассуждали о
theory of probability No, it turns out that I,
теории вероятности нет получается я
avoiding a
уходя от
blow, avoiding a blow, it turns out the car
удара уходя от удара получается машина в
went into the ice on my  side this means this is
гололёд пошла на мою сторо это значит
geometry leaving this is there
это геометрия уходя это же там по
tangentially Came out yes this is already geometry
касательное Вышли да это уже геометрия
No no I tried to get
Нет нет я старался чтобы своей большой
away from the impact with my big car and I went to the side of the road
машиной уйти от удара и я ушёл в обочину
and
и балкой
caught a big pile of pony with the beam the
поймал большую кучу поня
road is straight everything the road is straight Yes and you
прямая всё дорога это прямая Да а вы
left tangentially That is already
ушли по касательной То есть это уже
geometry all this already Yes we figured out the
геометрия всё это уже Да мы разобрали
theory of p that you cant take other people's souls not
теория р что не забрать чужие души не
embarrassed 50 tons with cargo and so as not to
стесняша 50 тонн с грузом и чтоб не
take people from a car I tried to
забрать людей с легковушки Я старался
leave and how it turned out that I
уйти и как бы получилось что у меня
just simply hit the front beam and I
просто просто удар переднюю балку и я
went out through the windshield understood and after that you
вышел через лобовое понял и у вас после
discovered mathematical
этого открылись математические
abilities that you didnt have at school so
способности которых не было в школе так
yes no as if I always thought well
да нет как бы я всегда считал хорошо
always thought well Cool yeah But
всегда считали хорошо Прикольно да А вот
these views of yours on
эти ваши воззрения на
there from what age do you think in
там с какого возраста вы мыслите
geometric progression
геометрической прогрессией
Oh well I always tried to somehow pull
О ну я всегда старался как бы вытащить
myself out of this
себя из этой
always earned
всегда зарабатывал пытался
money tried to buy something
деньги что-то покупать
move improve my purchases in the
передвигаться улучшать свои покупки в
sense of resale
смысле
in the sense of bought fixed
перепродажа в смысле купил починил
sold so the question And what did I ask you
продал так вопрос А что я вас спросил
stop  what did I
стоп что я вас
ask you What do you mean geometric
спросил В смысле вы геометрическая
progression Yes I bought the goods smeared
прогрессия Да я купил дей товар намазал
his face
ему морду
resold bought more
перепродал купил более
expensive also restored sold everything I
дороже также восстановил продал всё
understood this is geometric progression
понял вот это геометрическая прогрессия
and money multiplies in geometric
и бабки множатся в геометрической
progression That is you A I understood everything
прогрессии То есть вы А всё я понял
In short everything is mathematical mathematically
Короче всё математически математически
it looks like this is how it looks you buy a broken
это Так выглядит ты покупаешь битую
car repairs it sell you buy
тачку ремонтирует её продаёшь покупаешь
two broken cars repairs them sell
две битых Тачки ремонтирует их продаёшь
probably a better car Well like let's do it
поди более лучшую тачку Ну типа давай
so that we visualize two cars
так чтобы мы визуализировать две Тачки
Yes Yes Now and you fix yes
Да Да Теперь и и чинишь да
repairs now four cars twice as
ремонтирует теперь четыре тачки в два
much you sell four cars Yes you sell 4 you buy 8 you sell
раза больше продаёшь четыре Тачки Да
eight you buy 16 you sell 16 you buy 32 you sell 32 you buy 64 you sell 64 you get 128 you sell 128 you get 512
продаёшь 4 покупаешь 8 продаёшь восем
oh 256 you sell 256 you get 512
ой 256 продаёшь 256 получаешь 512
sell 512 get 1024 Yes, you
продаёшь 512 получаешь 1024 Да у тебя
understand Well, in principle, that's it Well, not that And how Well,
понима Да ну в принципе то Ну не то А
tell me No I just took a cheaper one, fixed it,
расскажи Не я просто более дешёвую взял
worked on it, sold a more expensive one, took it,
починил поработал продал более дорогую
fixed an even
взял починил ещё
bigger one Well, I started with my first
большую вот я начинал у меня первая
car It was a ZIL 130 So And now what are you
машина Это был ЗИЛ 130 так А сейчас ты
selling Well, now I have, like,
продаёшь Ну у меня сейчас как бы
California and I don't want to sell it, that
Калифорния и я не хочу его продать а то
is, you stopped the business, a geometric
есть ты остановил бизнес геометрическая
progression, like, tied it up No, how would
прогрессия типа завязал её Да нет как бы
you say that this is the last term of a geometric progression
это у тебя получается последний член
No, I
геометрической прогрессии Да нет он мне
like it because I bought a
нравится потому что я на него купил
new
новый
engine for it, a brand new Kamenets installed it in it
мотор прям новенький Каменец установил в
and how would I work on a tired engine Yes, it
него и как бы я да на уставшем моторе
ate oil, as if there
работал да он у меня кушал масло как бы
was an expense for consumables But you,
там затрата была на расходник ж а ты ты
you didn't invest somewhere in
ты не инвестировал куда-то в ценные
securities, in short, in
бумаги в какие-то короче
gold, interest in banks Didn't put No, I do
золото проценты в банки не ложил Не ну я
n't know, maybe an investor there, that is, you
не знаю может инвестор там то есть ты
invest, this is my profession Well,
инвестирует это моя профессия как бы да
I'm hauling there now, I have a trailer and
я сейчас таскаю там у меня есть прицеп и
reri there
рери
is a cigar sri Did I understand correctly that you
есть сигара сри Я правильно понял что ты
now you started to repair ZIL yourself
сейчас ты начинал сам ЗИЛ ремонтировать
Now you already have assistants who
Теперь у тебя уже есть помощники которые
you hire it's all like here is your
их ты нанимает это всё типа вот твой
vehicle fleet I trust I just myself that is I don't
автопарк доверяю я просто сам то есть не
trust So that the business is not squeezed out it
доверяешь Чтобы бизнес не отжали
turns out yes not taken away No No No you
получается да не увели Нет Нет Нет
understand If you want to do it well Do
понимаешь Если хочешь сделать хорошо
it
Сделай это
yourself correctly
сам правильно
correct Not a
правильно Не
fact a
факт
fact you understand Here you hire a person
факт понимаешь Вот ты нанимает человека
yes
да
he Stop stop stop wait I have already
онпп Стоп стоп стоп подожди я уже
lost the meaning of why I talked to you
потерял смысл ради чего я с тобой
Well we kind of started the topic in general
общался Ну мы как бы тему начали вообще
from geometric progression of course yes
от геометрической прогрессии конечно да
a little I'm just looking I'm by the way
немножко я я просто смотрю я по ме
Zhenya name how can I
кстати Женька зовут как я могу к вам
contact you Andrey
обращаться Андрей
Vasilyevich Well Andryukha not Andrey
Васильевич Ну Андрюха не Андрей
Vasilyevich m well I haven't grown up to Evgeny
Васильевич м ну я же не дорос до Евгения
Valerievich Well you haven't grown up I have grown up I am
Валерьевича Ну ты не дорос я дорос я
still a respectable person deputy like well it's
всё-таки солидный человек депутат типа
not fused for me to Andr Andrey
ну мне не слитно чтобы Андр Андрей
Vasilyevich everyone
Васильевич меня все
calls me Well nem yes to a mandate it's generally
называют Ну нем да до мандата то вообще
difficult well say so Andrey Vasilyevich
тяжело ну так говори Андрей Васильевич
contact Well well everything is possible come on
обращайся Ну ну всё возможно давай
try to say Andrey Vasilyevich I
попробуй скажи Андрей Васильевич я ж вас
personally don't don't don't have a tongue
лично не не не у меня язык
And what what I can't bring myself to do with my tongue
просто А что что с языком не
what with my tongue do you understand
поворачивается что с языком понимаете вы
you my age how old are you I'm
вы моего возраста тебе сколько лет мне
35 Well, what age are you a
мне мне 35 Ну всё какого возраста Ты
minor I was
малолетка я восемьдесят первого года
born in 1981 And when were you born it
рождения А ты ещё когда родился
turns out in 1987 or
получается в восемьдесят седьмом или
1988 1989
восемьдесят восьмом восемьдесят девятом
Andrey Vasilyevich understood Call me
Андрей Васильевич понял Называй меня
Andrey Vasilyevich
Андрей Васильевич
by social status deputy yes And you're a
по социальному статусу депутат да А ты
businessman wait No don't look And
бизнесмен те подожди Нет не смотри А
look you're a
смотрите ты малыш
thirty-year-old kid And what's next I'm an older
тридцатилетний И что дальше я старший
man 42 years old With respect Speak
мужчина 42 года С уважением Говори
Andrey
Андрей
Vasilyevich there are no tens Andrey
Васильевич десятки нету Андрей
Vasilyevich once
Васильевич ещё
again in different periods bench press yes
раз разных периодах жим дава
so because because you're trying to
так потому потому что ты пытаетесь
show your you saw etiquette you
показать сво ты этикет видел ты этикет
read etiquette to elders you need
читал к старшим нужно
skills and by name patronymic was at
навы и по имени отчеству было как
least 15-20 years old by name patronymic
минимум 15-20 лет по имени отчеству
Andrey Vasilyevich said or Now I
Андрей Васильевич сказал или Сейчас
'll switch
переключу
you over come on come on learn etiquette
тебя давай добро давай учи этикет
shameless good
бессовестный
luck
удачи
mathematician Hello Hello to you by  18
математик Здрав Здравствуйте Вам по 18
years old yes yes yes about I am from the city of
лет есть имеется имеется о Я из города
Khmelnitsky where are you from We are from Novosibirsk
Хмельницке Вы откуда Мы из Новосибирска
I understand let's talk normally but
понял давайте нормально поговорим да не
let's not quarrel Is it true that
будем ссориться А это правда что там
Novosibirsk was sitting without this without
Новосибирск сидел без это без
heating that there was a breakthrough something and there was there was
отопления что там прорыва что-то а было
Well there was a breakthrough something for a
было было Ну там прорвало что-то на
week already well somehow in short it didn't
недельку уже ну как-то нас короче не
affect us in general I understand I understand And are you
затронул в общем понял понял А вы
some kind of pagans there what do I see there
какие-то язычники там что вижу там
symbols No well a pagan rune
символы Нет ну руна языческая
Scandinavian Scandinavian sign You are
скандинавский скандинавский знак Ты там
like one Thor In short you are on them there yes Well
типа один Тор Короче ты на них там да Ну
in the sense like you like them well I would
в смысле типа нравятся они тебе
n't say that I directly believe in it I just
ну не сказал бы что я прямо верю в это
like this all well
просто нравится именно вот это вот всё
like for girls it's cooler yes like
ну типа для девчонок так прикольнее да
No such thing Yes no for myself purely for
типа Неу такое Да нет для себя чисто для
myself I understand yes and how do you communicate here Yes we listen Well we listen
себя понял да а чём общаетесь тут Да
yes Basically I
слушаем Ну слушаем да В основном
understand let's now if you listen to me
понял давайте сейчас буде будете меня
I will only ask leading questions
слушать я буду только наводящие вопросы
like look how do you feel about the
задавать такие смотрите как относитесь к
special military
специальной военной
operation ambiguous I agree it's
операции неоднозначно
ambiguous it's so there is no
неоднозначно это так что нет
definite point of view about who is to
определённой точки зрения что кто
blame who is right and what is unclear here
виноват кто прав а что тут непонятно
look let's do it this way Russia led its troops
смотри давай так Россия вела свои войска
on the territory of Ukraine and not vice versa
на территории Украины а не наоборот это
we know this we know what is not
мы знаем это мы знаем то что вам не
clear to you well what are all these political
ясно ну что все эти политические тонкие
subtleties All I don't understand about this is
моменты Всё я в этом не разбираюсь
just politics like it's complicated what is it So
просто политика типа сложно что такое
what is ambiguous look
Так а что неоднозначно смотри
ambiguous when you figured it out and
неоднозначно когда ты разобрался и
see that there is ambiguity if you do
видишь что там неоднозначность если ты
n't understand then everything is
ни не разбираешься то тут всё
unambiguous Well he knows yes Ask
однозначно Ну знает да Спроси у
him who he has Well well the neighbor
него кого у него Да ну у соседа
with what do you think Well since it started then
с что ты думаешь Ну раз она началась
its reasons came but
значит на то и свои причины пришла но
nothing like that just doesn't happen to me
ничего так мне просто так не происходит
in this world Cool And look for example
в этом мире Прикольно А смотри например
if you are walking By the way you have
если ты идёшь У тебя кстати волосы
long short hair
длинные недлинные
Yes we have SBO they are long long Yes
Да у нас СБО они длинные длинные Да вот
you are walking shorter and passing by the bus
ты идёшь короче да проходишь возле
stop some guys are standing Shorter guys
остановки стоят какие-то Короче пацаны
Yes they say a hairy guy is walking they took shorter
Да говорят идёт волосатый взяли короче
you shorter yes like yeah well what do you
тебя короче да типа да ну как ты
think this is since you means this was also a
считаешь это раз тебя значит это тоже на
reason Well I grew long hair there
причина Ну я отрастил длинные волосы
was a reason but not a justified one
причина была но не обоснованная
and who is to blame the one who took
а кто виноват тот кто
you for your hair or is this also
тебя за твои волосы или это тут тоже
ambiguous here Well who it turns out
неоднозначно Ну кто получается
that is when you try it on your own
о то есть когда ты примеряешь на свою у
you have everything immediately clearly yes when
тебя всё однозначно сразу стоет да когда
here the analogy is very good you immediately
тут аналогия очень хоро тебя сразу там
shrank and in short immediately the blood went to the brain
сжался и короче сразу кровь пошла в мозг
and immediately began to understand everything really who is the
и сразу всё начал понимать правда кто
aggressor is to
агрессор тот и
blame comparing the war with what is at the bus
виноват сравнивать войну с тем что на
stop is strange And what is not so
остановке это странно А что тут не так
much inappropriate here there is aggression and there is
много не подходящего там агрессия и там
aggression there is a victim and an
агрессия там есть жертва и натель
attacker and here it is one thing when you just
нападник и тут одно дело когда ты просто
roughly speaking to you at the bus stop and another
тебя грубо говоря на остановке а другое
thing when you at the world level take and
дело когда ты на мировом уровне берёшь и
declare to the country Who Nobody declared
объявляет стране Кто Никто не объявляла
Russia just took and attacked Ukraine did
Россия просто взяла и напала на Украину
not declare any war special operation
не объявляла никакую войну спецоперация
special operation is going on so there is no war so they
спецоперация же идёт так войны нету вот
took and attacked Well look in
взяли и напали Хорошо смотри стоят
short thugs are standing at the bus stop and declaring Let's go
короче гопники на остановке и объявляют
Now these two are now
Давай мы пойдём Вот этим двум сейчас
in short
короче
shelling them a bottle of beer and they went
обстрелом им бутылку из-под пива и пошли
declared and went how is it different and
объявили и пошли чем это отличается и
there and there they took and attacked
там и там взяли и напали
strange analogies of course Well how
на странные аналогии конечно Ну как
strange analogies well really look Toto there are
странные аналогии ну реально смотри Тото
thugs Yes there is
есть гопники Да есть
yours they come You didn't do anything to them
твоя они приходят Вот ты им ничего не
you  in short, they didn't like
делал ты короче вот им не понравилось
what was wrong with you They they they say Get a haircut Get a haircut
что твоего Они они они говорят
Yes, you say,
Постригись Постригись Да ты говоришь
damn, well, this is my hairstyle I want to
блин ну это моя причёска Я хочу так и
walk like this They took you, caught you, cut off
ходить они взяли тебя поймали срезают
the mop there, in short, that's it, you'll walk around
там швабру короче что всё будешь ходить
bald now Your
теперь лысый
eyes are so wide it
там у тебя глаза так расширились такое
feels like you're dreaming It seems like you're
ощущение как ты мечтаешь Вроде ты аж
really going through
реально прокручивает это
all of this That is, Ukraine, it's
всё то есть Украина это
not me I'm looking, it's just that in your eyes I
не я смотрю просто в твоих глазах я
saw not so much pain as
увидел не столько боль сколько
real inspiration Yes, it's a funny joke, but [ __ ] And you
реально Да это смешная шутка а сри А вас
once Well, come on, seriously, you
когда-то Ну давай если серьёзно вас
once were beaten by punks for your appearance,
когда-то вот гопники за внешность били
like, for example, Domakha on the
типа например домахи на
street Well, yes, but they didn't beat you, that is, it didn't
улице Ну да но не били то есть не
get to that And how did you get away How did you avoid
доходило А как вы отма Как вы избегали
beatings
побоев
When you weigh 90 kg and are 2 m tall,
Когда в тебе 90 кг веса и 2 м роста до
you're not the one by the hair And the second
тебя не за волосы А второго
one is smaller and lighter Yes, a boxer Well,
он поменьше и полегче Да боксёр Ну
first of all, yes, secondly, there simply wasn't a
во-первых да во-вторых просто не было
situation when it would have gotten to that And
ситуации когда доходило бы до этого А
how A Well, tell me how it was that you
как А Ну расскажи как вот было что тебе
Domakha by the hair there, not really, so as not to
Домаха за волосы там не прям чтоб не
straight what Yes of course Just somehow
прям что Да конечно Просто как-то
mentioned in passing dialogue or something I do
упоминали вскользь диалога что ли Я уже
n't remember what I answered to this like
не помню что я отвечал на это типа
just well like you shouldn't have what
просто ну типа тебя не должно какие
hair and all that Yeah sweat Well everyone and
волосы всё такое Ага пот Ну всё и
left
уходили
Yes yes there was no
Да да там не было
aggression Nobody particularly I just saw in
агрессивного Никто особо Я просто видел
short in this city of Elektrostal there they
короче в это в городе Электросталь там с
took off some punk in short
когото панка сняли короче
like his hair was dyed like he had Well
типа волосы крашеные были типа у него Ну
this is more of an out of the ordinary case he's out of the ordinary
это скорее случай из ряда он выходящий
Well how out of the ordinary they took like they wanted to take it off it
Ну как из ряда взяли типа захотели сня
turns out nope
получается неня
but look it turns out you're a boxer And you're
а смотри получается ты боксёр А ты
ninety kilograms yeah Well something like
девяносто килограммовый да Ну что-то в
that Can you stand up so that I
таком духе А можешь встать чтобы я ну
really 2 meters tall just can't see
реально 2 Мет роста просто так не видно
like come on What can I
типа давай Что я могу для сравнения
stand up for comparison Well Stand up for
встать Ну Встаньте для
comparison Well stand up Yes next to him for
сравнения Ну встань Да возле него для
comparison
сравнения
so that Well yes like you you rather like you
чтобы Ну да типа тебе тебе скорее типа
need and my Wait if you're a boxer
надо а мо Вот подожди если ты боксёр
give him a two in the belly Well let's give him
проведи двоечку ему в пузо Ну напри
a two in the belly But he'll die I'll die yeah so oh
двоечку ему в пузо Да он же умрёт я умру
kg Well the belly is not ninety kilograms And
кг Ну пузо то не девяносто килограммовое
you on  who are you
А вы на кого
studying I'm a lawyer and the second is a lawyer
учитесь Я на юристы а второй юрист
lawyers prosecutor's office there lawyer
юристы прокурорская там юрист
[laughter]
[смех]
lawyer what
юрист какой
year first first
курс первый первый
and have you known each other for a long time
а Вы давно
yes that's how long since September 1st and that
знакомы да вот сколько с 1 сентября А то
is this and you are from different cities
есть это А вы с разных городов Да по
yes you came from one well like from different but
приезжали с одного Ну как бы с разных но
from one and from what city are you from
с одного А с какого города
such a Siberian wilderness well for
родом такая Сибирская глушинка Ну
example I don't know where the
например я же не знаю где
wilderness is Yurga rga so Yurga is not a city
глушинка Юрга рга так Юрга это не город
in my opinion like well that's
по-моему типа
like well that's not a city
а Ну это типа ну это не город Да
anyway in short I understood from
вообще короче понял с
frosty well yes I
морозных Ну ну да
understood heard stories about these regions
понял слышал истории про эти регионы
there yes yes it's scary there they
там там Да да страшно там по улицам
say not to walk on the streets in the evening
говорят вечером не
no it's fun there well something like you
ходить Нет там весело Ну
know how to pour pepper vodka it's very
того знаете как перцовкой заливать очень
interesting you poured pepper vodka yes Okay look come on let
интересно вы заливали перцовкой да
's get back to the questions of
смотри давай давай вернёмся к вопросам
geopolitics maybe it became
геополитики Может у
clear to us Yeah look after this
на прояснилось Да смотри вот после это
after the mops everything immediately became clearer Yeah
после швабр сразу всё понятнее стало Да
look if Russia led its troops into
смотри если Россия вела свои войска в
Ukraine then who is to blame Yeah
Украину да то кто виноват
I wouldn't say for sure
а Вот однозначно я бы не
Okay look if a thug
сказал Хорошо смотри если гопник тебе
introduces a mop to you who is to blame yes what does
введёт швабру Кто виноват да Причём
this have to do with it  yes this is an analogy but it is
здесь это да это аналогия но она она
too simple like since we give analogies you are
слишком простая типа раз мы аналогии
walking with your mother late in the evening
приводим ты идёшь с мамой поздно вечером
to you To her to you someone there you
до тебя До неё до вас кто-то там ты его
hit him very unpleasantly the asphalt He died they are
очень неприятно ударил асфальт Он умер
trying to put you in jail Well and they put you in
тебя пытаются посадить Ну и посадили по
jail as a result Well here many many analogies can be
итогу Ну тут много много аналогий можно
given the question of who is guilty not guilty
привести вопрос кто виноват не виноват
there everything is just just not everything is clear here
там всё как раз как раз не тут всё ясно
yes If he if for example he said a
да Если он если он например сказал мне
bad word to me and I went to him he died I am
плохое слово а я пошёл ему он умер я
guilty yes if I had self-defense
виноват да если у меня была самозащита
he attacked for example yes and I fought back here I am
он напал например да и я отбивался тут я
not guilty here everything is very clear You
не виноват тут всё очень чётко Вы же
Vili put you in jail not Why is the law the law the
Вили посадили тебя не Почему закон закон
law what the law is not I don't know you and what about
закон что закон не есть не знаю вас ви
We have an excess of
что с У нас есть превышение мер
permissible self-defense measures Yes I don't know what it's
допустимой самообороны Да не знаю как
called you yes that is you
оно вас называется вот да то есть ты
can defend yourself yes if you didn't have
можешь обороняться да если у тебя не
intent if he attacked you you
было умысла если он на тебя напал ты ему
hit him Yes and he staggered and
ударил его Да а он пошатнулся и где-то
fell somewhere Yes you didn't have intent you were
упал Да у тебя не было умысла ты
defending yourself Everything is fine Everything is self-defense
защищался Всё нормально Всё самооборона
if you hit him Yes he fell And you also
если ты его ударил Да он упал А ты ещё
jumped at him like yes then  you are
прыгал у него на типа да тогда ты
guilty
виноват
yes In court That's not how it usually works Well
да В суде Так это не работает обычно Ну
you have courts at all no your courts don't
у вас у вас вообще суды не у вас суды не
work you don't have a state based on the rule of law
работают у вас нету правового
Yes yes yes that is
государства Да да
we Criminal
да то есть мым Уголовный
Code ki
кодекс ки
constantly stuck a
постояно гла засунул
live chu take your hands out of there Damn I
живую чу забери руки оттуда Блин не
can't leave you a couple to love
могу оставлю вас парочка любить
Salom
Салом
myself Good evening I don't know what
сам Добрый вечер Я не знаю как у вас там
time it is where you are
время вы
from I am from
откуда я с
Grozny today so many Chechens came out
Грозного сегодня чеченцев столько вышло
to chat roulette to chatroulette What do you talk about
в чат рулетку в чатрулет О чём общаетесь
Well I have different things for example
Ну я разном например
differences What to talk about in general I'm interested in
разницы О чём общаться вообще мне
Where did we come from And what in
интересно А откуда мы взялись А и что
general well in terms of the physics of the earth I'm
вообще ну в плане физики земли мне
interested in and the geography of the earth I'm
интересно а и география земли мне
interested in Let's talk about the physics and
интересно Давайте поговорим о физике и
geography of the earth Where did you come from Where did
географии земли Откуда вы взялись Откуда
you
вы
come from No not us I meant we all
взялись Нет не мы Я имел в виду мы все
all Chechens I understand all Chechens I understand
все чеченцы я понял все чеченцы я понял
No all people all people Okay
Нет все люди все люди Окей
Dalyu what theory do you adhere to
Далю какой вы теории придерживаетесь
evolutionism creationism
эволюционизма креационизма
creationism I adhere to the theory of a
креационизма я придерживаюсь теории
flat
плоской
earth God, finally I found a person
земли Боже наконец-то я нашёл человека
who is close to me in spirit
который мне по духу близок духу
I am close to the spirit yes I read a lot
близок я да я очень много
about it I even kept a blog
об этом и читал Я даже блог вёл с меня
a lot of people laughed at me here in my
очень много людей смеялось тут у меня в
city Yes they said that I was some kind of
городе Да говорили что я какой-то
crazy yes but in recent years a
умалишённый да но последние годы очень
lot of truthful information has begun to appear
много начало появляться правдивее
and people have already begun to treat me
информации и ко мне уже начали
differently
по-другому относиться по-другому
This is sarcasm No
относиться Это сарказм Нет
no I listened to Yuri Laza and
нет я и Юрия лазу слушал
also
тоже
watched Ivin all his videos in
ивина смотрел его все ролики на
English
английском
that's for sure that's right that's for
это точно вот прямо вот
sure I just came to one point
точно Просто я пришёл к одному моменту
if 130 km high frequency the Earth rotates Why does
если 130 км ВЧ вращается Земля Почему
n't water shift to the Equator I started like that
вода не смещается на Экватор я начал
I asked a lot of questions and They
такие я я много вопросов задавал и Меня
began to simply ignore me they ignore me
начали просто игнорить меня игнорят
everywhere
везде
In short I have a lot of questions Me
Короче у меня очень много вопросов Я
too I always say they tell me you're
тоже Я всегда говорю вот мне говорят ты
making it up that is I say this
выдумываешь то есть я говорю так
answer me the question why is it like this yes
ответьте мне на вопрос почему так да
why and at this moment they simply
почему а в этот момент меня просто
ignore me yes after all if look if I say as I
игнорит да ведь если смотри если я как
say if you sit on the Carousel and
говорю если вы сядьте на Карусель и
turn off the Carousel At such a speed you will
Карусель расключить С такой скоростью вы
fly away Yes With these are my words you are
улетите Да С это мои слова ты мои слова
speaking my words now you are speaking my words  I
говоришь сейчас ты мои слова говоришь я
give this example to everyone spin spin you
всем Это привожу пример раскрути
will throw you out If the devil throws you out
раскрути тебя выкинет Коль тебя выкинет
and this is a carousel with a low
черт и это это каруселька с небольшой
speed and the earth which is 6.400 radius
скоростью а земля которая 6.400 радиус
to
до
kime yes yes yes and it also rushes after the
киме да дадада и она ещё несётся за за
sun with a huge speed yes yes they say that is not only does
солнцем с огромной скорость да да
it
говорят то есть мало того что она
spin it also flies around the sun And
крутится она ещё вокруг Солнца летает Да
even with a spiral speed at that
ещё со спиральной скоростью причём
Look when on a bicycle on a cycle
Смотри когда вот на велосипеде на
track or in a car you turn
велотреке или на машине ты заворачивает
you skid and
тебя заносит да и у тебя с велосипеда
things fall from your bicycle or car
или с машины падают вещи
and also when If our Earth goes around the
и также когда Если наша Земля обходит
Orbit and turns sharply it would also
Орбиту и резко заворачивает тоже так бы
fall like that I found you after all in this world there
падало я тебя нашёл всё-таки в этом мире
is a person who like me you are
всё-таки есть человек который как я ты
my brother I love you My brother you are my
мой брат я тебя люблю Брат мой ты мой
brother I will say So we we are not brothers we are like
брат я скажу Так мы мы не братья мы как
these warriors
бы эти ратники по
once I you Like a brother love
разу я тебя Как бра люб
zano leniye has You understand they were told you
зано ление имет Понимаешь им сказали вот
know how in church they said there is
знаеш как в церкви сказали вот там есть
So So they were told at school the earth is round
Так Так им в школе сказали земля круглая
and they are fools the earth is round they
и они дураки земля круглая
say here  What is your name so that How can I
твердят вот тебя как зовут чтоб Как к
address you Andrius Aus Andrius
тебе обращаться андриус аус
Andrius a minute is ticking or am I mixing something up
андриус минута идт или я что-то путаю
Where on earth are there no forests yes yes have you seen
Где на земле лесов нет да да ты видел
this film Yes I have Yes I have seen you have seen what
этот фильм Да видел Да видел ты видел
it showed yes What
что он показал да Что Что здесь
happened here Pushkin's cannons look what they are
происходило Пушкина пушки смотри что они
saying is there a question Where are the trees older than
говорят там ли вопрос Где деревья старше
years 500 that's it that's it
лет 500 вот вот вот вот
if all these ancient trees where did they
если эти все древние деревя куда они
go And have you heard the moments when about the
делись А ты слышал моменты когда про
Mayan druids and some other people
друидов Майя и ещё один какой-то народ
who Well before them there
который Ну до них никого не
was no one pyramids and
было пирамиды и
Yes at the same moment that is and I will
Да в один и тот же момент то есть и я
say more on ancient Chinese maps there is
больше скажу на древних китайских картах
no moon that's it's handsome
Луны нету нету Вот вот вот красавчик
because the moon begins to appear
потому что луна Начинает появляться
about 3 thousand years ago on
около 3 с чем-то тысяч лет назад на
maps Only why You are
картах Только почему Вот ты
great I swear I'm just
молодец Клянусь я просто меня просто
torn apart by what
раздирает какой
people understand
люди понимат
and
а
look let's take this mountain Kyle Kyle
смотри вот эту гору возьмём Кайла Кайла
in general Magic mountain Magic mountain
вообще Волшебная гора Волшебная гора
devil's mountain if we take Why are they
гора дьяволова если возьмём Почему они
so even and were  And look I can
такие ровные а были А смотри я тебе могу
give you one point where I will
один момент привести де в том что я
say more You look at the rivers Yes
больше скажу Ты посмотри как реки Да у
we have these former quarries nowhere
нас это бывшие карьеры нигде сорвался
flat-earthers broke such a
плоскоземельщики такой
letter find Telegram right now axis VN
пись най Telegram прям зараз ось ВН
apok this is very and very important YouTube is busy with
апок це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube заня
us through the SRG ORV in your ban and very
нас через срг ОРВ в твый бан и дуже
many videos I do not show people at times I do not
багато вдео не показую людям вчасно не
show information about streams so that
показуе информация про стримы тому для
we Mali operational links are
того щоб ми Мали оперативный звязок
written right now and while there in Telegram
пишиться прямо зараз а пок там в телегра
OKM videos there is also interesting and useful
окм видео ще теж цикава и корисна
information and we are obliged to you trimati
информация и мы повинни з вами тримати
constant operational links
постийний оперативный звязок
independently in that chi will show you the process
незалежно в того чи покаже вам проце
YouTube Glory to Ukraine
YouTube Слава Украине
write A
пиши A